Guide to the Civic Club of Allegheny County Records, 1896-1974 AIS.1970.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Original 1970 and 1971 Donations, 1898-1960; I.
  - O'Connell, Dr. C. Leonard, undated (Box 27, Folder 252)
  - Philips, Samuel E., undated (Box 27, Folder 253)
  - Rea, James C., undated (Box 27, Folder 254)
  - Scurlock, J. Paul, undated (Box 27, Folder 255)
  - Stevens, Thomas Wood, undated (Box 27, Folder 256)
  - Thaw, Mrs. William, Jr., undated (Box 27, Folder 257)
  - Wells, Carveth, undated (Box 27, Folder 258)
  - Miscellaneous Publications from Civic and City Clubs Outside of Pittsburgh, undated (Box 27, Folder 259)
- Civic Club of Allegheny County History, 1895-1974; II.
  Scope and Content Notes
  In 1890 the Women's Health Protective Association of Allegheny County was created by a group of Pittsburgh women in an effort to ban public spitting, clean up air pollution, and create a regular garbage collection program. This was the first civic organization in Pennsylvania. In 1895 the Association became the Civic Club of Allegheny County and began to admit men as members in order to better influence the government. Until its dissolution in 1974, the Civic Club was maintained by caring citizens of Allegheny County as they worked to ensure that the region became a cleaner, healthier and more desirable place to live. Their mission was carried out through various programs and events detailed throughout the collection.
  To expand on the club's beginnings, these records contain the club charter, by-laws and constitution. Different programs and events presented by the Civic Club were also scattered throughout its rich history. Included are documents about Stephen Foster Day and affiliate Civic Clubs just to name a couple of the programs represented in this series. Correspondence and clippings concerning the Civic Club's 25th, 50th, and 75th anniversaries are also present as well as correspondence of Civic Club presidents Schuchman, Gallup, Everstine and Murdock. The dissolution of the Civic Club is alluded to in correspondence regarding a canceled boat ride. Photographs of the Christmas tree lightings, the Open-Air School, Daycare, and the Civic Club office are also present. Ephemeral items include the club's meeting gavel and an Allegheny County flag.
  - Civic Club of Allegheny County Historical Background, 1916-1970 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Civic Club Annual Meetings, 1896-1911 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Civic Club By-Laws, 1896 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Copy of Civic Club Charter, 1896 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Charter Members and Contributors, 1895 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Proposed Amendments to By-Laws and Club Reorganization, 1901-1943 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Clippings- Civic Club History, 1902-1915 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Letters and Circulars, 1907-1913 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Letter to Civic Club from Dr. C.C. Wholey, 1907 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence of H.M. Dermitt, 1908-1930 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Civic Club Legal Documents, 1908-1972 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Photos of Civic Club Daycare, 1911 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Open Air Schools, 1911-1917 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Amendments to Club Policies, 1913 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Letter to Civic Club Board of Directors from Oliver McClintock, 1914 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Letter and Report Regarding Adam's Market, 1915 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Guarantee Fund, 1915 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Photos of the Club Float at the County Anniversary, 1916 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Clippings- Civic Club of Allegheny County 25th Anniversary, 1920 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Officer, Directors and Committee List and Club History, 1920-1939, 1948 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Junior Civic Clubs, 1921-1922 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Latimer Junior High Health Week, 1922 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Speech- Mayor Magee to Civic Club, 1924 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Stephen Foster Day, 1926 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, Reports and Bulletins Regarding the Board, 1927-1965 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Christmas Lights, 1929-1933 (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - "Civic Club of Allegheny County 1895-1935" (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - Charter Revision Booklet, 1936 (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - Civic Club Membership and Club Goals, 1938 (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - Civic Club of Allegheny County Constitution, ca.1938, ca.1958 (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - Questionnaire and Correspondence, 1938-1968 (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - Letter and Clippings Regarding the Golden Jubilee Program, 1939 (Box 28, Folder 32)
  - "Civic Affairs" Bulletin, 1939-1948 (Box 28, Folder 33)
  - "Fifty Years of Civic Club History: 1895-1945" (Box 28, Folder 34)
  - Clippings- Civic Club of Allegheny County 50th Anniversary, 1945 (Box 28, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence Regarding 50th Anniversary Contributions and to Founding Members, 1945 (Box 28, Folder 36)
  - Proposed New Civic Club Constitution, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence of F.E. Schuchman, 1947-1967 (Box 28, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence of E.H. Gallup, Jr., 1951-1952 (Box 28, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence of A. Perry Everstine, 1952-1955 (Box 28, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence of Hazel B. Scott, 1953-1956 (Box 28, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence with Organizations and Companies, 1952-1969 (Box 28, Folder 42)
  - Proposed Site for Pittsburgh Civic Light Opera, 1952 (Box 28, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence of Jacob M. Murdock, 1954-1956 (Box 28, Folder 44)
  - American Planning and Civic Association Honor Roll Certificate, 1954 (Box 28, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence- Acceptance of Committee Chairs, 1955 (Box 28, Folder 46)
  - Letter to Old Members and Past Committee List, 1957, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 47)
  - Civic Club of Allegheny County General History, 1958 (Box 28, Folder 48)
  - Documents Regarding a Civic Club Name Change, 1965-1966 (Box 28, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence of F.E. Schuchman and Flick-Reedy, 1966 (Box 28, Folder 50)
  - Stationary Samples, 1966-1974 (Box 28, Folder 51)
  - All-America Cities Awards Competition Allegheny County Application, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 52)
  - North Braddock Tax Payers Protective Association Correspondence and Reports, 1969-1972 (Box 28, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence with Legislators and Organizations, 1970-1973 (Box 28, Folder 54)
  - Memoranda and Correspondence, 1971-1974 (Box 28, Folder 55)
  - Turtle Creek Civic Club Correspondence and Bulletins, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 56)
  - Civic Club of Allegheny County 75th Anniversary, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 57)
  - Correspondence with Affiliate Civic Clubs, 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 58)
  - Concerned Tax Payers of Allegheny County Memoranda, Member List and Clippings, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 59)
  - National Information Bureau Report, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 60)
  - Letters of Thanks from John H. Neely, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 61)
  - Cancelled Boat Ride, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 62)
  - Photo of Civic Club Office at Hotel William Penn, undated (Box 28, Folder 63)
  - Miscellaneous Club Events and Honors, undated (Box 28, Folder 64)
  - Article, "Civic Organizations: Why? Where? How?", undated (Box 28, Folder 65)
  - Correspondence between Club President and Members, undated (Box 28, Folder 66)
  - Civic Club Subscription Cards, undated (Box 28, Folder 67)
  - Gavel, undated (Box 28, Other 1)
  - Flag of Allegheny County, undated (Box 28, Other 2)
  - Annals of the Civic Club Vol.3, undated (Box 28, Other 3)
- Board of Directors Minutes, 1895-1974; III.
  The Board of Directors for the Civic Club typically met once a month. The club president presided over the meetings which were attended by committee chairs, the club secretary, and any other speaker or special guest for which attendance had been arranged. At these meetings the Board of Directors discussed the plans and reports of several committees, approved club budgets and expenses, and were updated on new members as well as member resignations and deaths. Updates on proposed legislation and club programs, such as Exceptionally Able Youth and the Voters' Directory, were also presented. Occasionally the Board of Directors would hold special meetings when an issue required the club take an immediate stance. One such issue was that of the proposed privatization of garbage collection. In that case, the Civic Club decided to oppose the proposal due to their longstanding support of a city managed system. The Board of Directors minutes span the Civic Club's entire existence (1895-1974). Original minute books were maintained from 1895 to 1943 with handwritten minutes until 1914. Between 1914 and 1944, the club's secretary typed drafts of minutes and glued them into the minute books. Starting in 1944, minute books were no longer used and typed minutes were placed in folders.
  Along with the Board of Directors minutes are reports regarding Civic Club finances, membership and the Soho Bath House. These minutes and reports help illustrate the activities and concerns, as well as the organization and business behind the politically and socially active Civic Club. Biographical information on some of the Board of Directors members from 1970 is also present.
  - Index to Board of Directors Minute Books, 1895-1899, 1918-1924 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Materials for an Index to Board of Directors Minute Book, 1899-1909 (Box 29, Folder 02-04)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1899, 1903 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors Minute Books, 1895-1924 (Box 29, Volume 1-13)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1924-1945 (Box 30, Volume 01-12)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes and Reports, 1944-1974 (Box 31, Folder 01-38)
  - Board of Directors Mailing List, 1969-1972 (Box 31, Folder 39)
  - Board Member Biographies, 1970-1971 (Box 31, Folder 40)
- Committees, 1895-1974; IV.
  The Civic Club organized its members into committees in order to efficiently examine and create programs to solve problems concerning the welfare of Allegheny County. An example of such is the Legislative Committee which studied and proposed legislation that would be presented in the State House of Representatives and Senate. Other committees assisted in maintaining the Civic Club itself, such as the Membership Committee which was in charge of gaining new members as well as retaining active members, an essential function of the club.
  These records contain lists of committees and subcommittees along with its mission and objectives. Also present are committee meeting minutes including original handwritten minute books of the Education Department of the Civic Club from 1896 to 1909 and committee members lists and reports.
  Folders 41-50 are concerned with the affairs of several committees and arranged chronologically. The remaining files are arranged alphabetically by committee name and then chronologically. This series contains two subseries concerning the Membership and Public Relations Committees.
  - Committees, general, 1895-1973
    - Report about Committees and Committee Listing, 1895-1910 (Box 31, Folder 41)
    - Board of Directors and Officers List and Attendance Record, 1918-1919 (Box 31, Folder 42)
    - Board and Committee Member List and Objectives, 1939-1942 (Box 31, Folder 43-44)
    - Committee Duties and Responsibilities, 1944 (Box 31, Folder 45)
    - Committee and Subcommittee Member Lists and Reports, ca.1947 (Box 31, Folder 46)
    - Committee Duties and Objectives, undated (Box 31, Folder 47)
    - Annual Report of Mrs. Iams, Chairman Department of Social Science, 1907 (Box 31, Folder 48)
    - Various Committee Reports, 1913-1914 (Box 31, Folder 49-50)
    - Advisory Committee Report, 1958 (Box 31, Folder 51)
    - 14th Annual Meeting of National Municipal League and American Civic Association, 1908 (Box 31, Folder 52)
    - Annual Meeting Committee Reports and Minutes, 1911-1949 (Box 31, Folder 53-58)
    - Annual Meeting Speech by David L. Lawrence, 1958 (Box 31, Folder 59)
    - Annual Membership Meeting, 1928-1974 (Box 32, Folder 01-03)
    - Better Housing Committee, 1952-1953 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - City and County Budget Committees, 1952-1955 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Committee Chairmen Meeting Minutes, 1916 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Education Department Meeting Minutes and Reports, 1896-1940 (Box 32, Folder 07-13)
    - Election of Officers Ballot, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Federation of Charities Minutes, 1907-1908 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Finance Committee Meeting Transcript, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Government Reorganization Committee Correspondence and Reports, ca. 1955 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Juvenile Court Committee Reports, 1908 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Legislative Committee Reports and Minutes, 1901-1973 (Box 32, Folder 19-28)
    - Legislative Committee Member List and Miscellaneous Papers, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 29)
  - Library Committee, 1938, 1954 (Box 32, Folder 30)
    - Membership List by Year, 1895-1960 (Box 32, Folder 31)
    - Original Index of Civic Club Members, 1898-1902 (Box 32, Folder 32)
    - Original Index of Member Addresses and Board and Committee Members, 1898-1902 (Box 32, Folder 33)
    - Original Index of Members and Paid Dues, 1904-1907 (Box 32, Folder 34)
    - Kate Cassatt McKnight Report and Letter, 1905, 1934 (Box 32, Folder 35)
    - Kate Cassatt McKnight "In Memoriam" booklet, 1907 (Box 32, Folder 36)
    - List of Civic Club Members, 1911 (Box 32, Folder 37)
    - Requests for New Members, 1918 (Box 32, Folder 38)
    - Clippings- Membership Campaign, 1920 (Box 32, Folder 39)
    - Membership Campaign, 1920 (Box 32, Folder 40)
    - Dr. John and Phoebe Brashear, 1925 (Box 32, Folder 41)
    - List of Original Civic Club Members and Living Relatives, 1945 (Box 32, Folder 42)
    - Membership Reports, 1953-1955 (Box 32, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence- Individual Membership, 1967-1972 (Box 32, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence- Membership Applications, Dues and Cancellation, 1967, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence- Corporate Membership, 1968-1970 (Box 32, Folder 46)
    - Membership Solicitation, 1969-1973 (Box 32, Folder 47)
    - Membership Drive, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 48)
    - Photo of Members with County Commissioners, ca.1972 (Box 32, Folder 49)
    - Photos of Members at a Club Dinner, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 50)
    - Biographies of Prominent Members, undated (Box 32, Folder 51)
    - Member Photos A-Z, undated (Box 32, Folder 52-53)
    - Correspondence- Affiliate and Associate Membership, undated (Box 32, Folder 54)
    - Members Listed by Legislative District, undated (Box 32, Folder 55)
    - Noon Luncheon Minutes, 1966-1967 (Box 32, Folder 56)
    - Public Health and Welfare Committee, 1949 (Box 32, Folder 57)
    - Public Relations, Clippings, 1914-1972 (Box 32, Folder 58)
    - Public Relations, News Releases, 1952-1970 (Box 32, Folder 59)
    - Public Relations, Correspondence with Television and Radio Stations, 1966, 1969 (Box 32, Folder 60)
    - Public Relations, Public Relations Collage, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 61)
    - Public Relations,Correspondence and Policies Regarding Civic Club Ads, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 62)
    - Public Relations, Re-evaluation Committee Minutes and Reports, 1951-1954 (Box 32, Folder 63-64)
    - Public Relations, Welfare Bond Issue Citizens' Committee, 1928 (Box 32, Folder 65)
    - Public Relations, Zoning Committee Reports, 1954 (Box 32, Folder 66)
- Metropolitan Plan, 1910-1959; V.
  Beginning in the 1910s, one of the Civic Club's main concerns was that of a Metropolitan Plan for the Pittsburgh area. If adopted, this plan would gather all the municipalities of Allegheny County under the collective government and title of Pittsburgh. By accepting the Metropolitan Plan, small municipalities could retain their name and have an equal share in government instead of risking later annexation by Pittsburgh without these benefits. This would have made Greater Pittsburgh the fourth largest city in the country. The issue was heavily researched and supported in the early twentieth century, but it appears that efforts began to taper as the 1950s came to a close.
  Included are Metropolitan Plan Committee minutes, pamphlets outlining the benefits of a metropolitan Pittsburgh, correspondence and reports regarding other cities with a metropolitan plan, and proposed Metropolitan Plan Charters.
  - Pittsburgh Civic Commission Correspondence, 1910 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Metropolitan Plan Mounted Pamphlets, 1919, 1928-1929 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Reports Regarding Metropolitan Plans of Other Cities, 1919-1928 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Metropolitan Plan Correspondence and Articles, 1920, 1927 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Metropolitan Legislation Correspondence and Reports, 1920-1926 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - "Metropolitan Organization of Municipal Activities" Report by Civic Development Department, 1924 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Commission to Study Municipal Consolidation in Counties of the Second Class in Allegheny County, 1924-1925 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Metropolitan Plan Organization Charts and Tables, 1927 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - William A. Magee Report on Metropolitan Planning and Resulting Correspondence, 1927 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Metropolitan Plan Recreation Welfare, 1928 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Pittsburgh Federation of Social Agencies Correspondence and Reports Regarding Metropolitan Plan, 1928 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence- Metropolitan Plan, 1928-1929 (Box 33, Folder 12-15)
  - Appeal of Metropolitan Plan Commission to Pennsylvania Supreme Court, 1929 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Abstract of Proposed Metropolitan Plan Charter, 1929 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Letters from Civic Club Members Approving the Metropolitan Charter, 1929 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - "Bibliography on the Reorganization and Consolidation of Local Government", 1934 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - County Management by Wylie Kilpatrick, 1935 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Metropolitan Plan Committee Minutes and Transcripts, 1935 (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - Metropolitan Plan Reports and Correspondence, 1935, 1938 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - City and County Consolidation Pamphlets for New York City and Philadelphia, 1935-1936 (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - Metropolitan Plan Reports, 1935, 1940 (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous Metropolitan Plan Pamphlets, undated (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - Tentative Draft of Metropolitan Charter, 1939 (Box 33, Folder 26)
  - Metropolitan Plan Correspondence and Articles, 1946, 1952 (Box 33, Folder 27)
  - Report of the Metropolitan Study Commission, 1955 (Box 33, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence- Metropolitan Plan, 1955-1959 (Box 33, Folder 29)
  - Reports Regarding Metropolitan Consolidation in Other Cities, undated (Box 33, Folder 30)
- Home Rule, 1919-1974; VI.
  In addition to the Metropolitan Plan, the Civic Club spent much of its time since the 1920s promoting the idea of Home Rule in Allegheny County. The concept of Home Rule maintains that a city or county would draft its own charter, thus allowing the city or county, instead of the state, to dictate how its government will be structured. In the 1970s "Pittsburgh, Yes" and the Government Study Commission were assembled to discuss Home Rule and some of their reports and minutes are present in this series. Political parties refused to proclaim their support or opposition toward Home Rule, thus discouraging voters from supporting the issue in local ballots. In 1974 a Home Rule charter was passed in the city of Pittsburgh.
  Besides commission reports and minutes, other records include proposed Home Rule bills and charters, news clippings, reports about Home Rule in other cities, the Pittsburgh Package Bill, and transcripts from State House and Senate hearings about Home Rule.
  - Clippings- Home Rule, 1919-1972 (Box 33, Folder 31-34)
  - Proposed Home Rule Charters, 1922, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 35)
  - Reports on Home Rule, 1922-1955 (Box 33, Folder 36)
  - Home Rule in Other Cities, 1923-1947 (Box 33, Folder 37)
  - Home Rule Bill Reports and Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 33, Folder 38)
  - Senate Bill Regarding Home Rule, 1941 (Box 33, Folder 39)
  - Transcripts Regarding Home Rule, 1941 (Box 33, Folder 40)
  - Home Rule Hearings in State House and Senate, 1941 (Box 33, Folder 41)
  - Letters Regarding Proportional Representation by George H. Hallett, Jr., 1943 (Box 33, Folder 42)
  - Report on City Fiscal Affairs, 1943 (Box 33, Folder 43)
  - Pittsburgh Package Bill, 1947 (Box 33, Folder 44)
  - Pittsburgh Package Correspondence, Reports and Minutes, 1947 (Box 33, Folder 45)
  - Government Consolidation in Allegheny County, ca.1958 (Box 33, Folder 46)
  - Urban Home Rule Charter for Allegheny County and Report, 1955 (Box 33, Folder 47)
  - Charter Panel Correspondence and Reports, 1955 (Box 33, Folder 48)
  - Citizens' Council for the County Charter Fact Book, 1957 (Box 33, Folder 49)
  - Lists Used in Building County Charter Committee, 1957 (Box 33, Folder 50)
  - "A Study of Civic Agencies in the Pittsburgh Area", 1958 (Box 33, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence- Home Rule, 1969-1974 (Box 33, Folder 52)
  - Home Rule Alliance for a "Yes" Vote, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 53)
  - Home Rule Charter Discussion Draft, 1973 (Box 33, Folder 54)
  - Home Rule Charter Preliminary and Discussion Drafts by George W. Shankey, Jr., 1973-1974 (Box 33, Folder 55)
  - Government Study Commission City of Pittsburgh Minutes, 1973-1974 (Box 33, Folder 56)
  - Government Study Commission of Allegheny County Reports Regarding Home Rule, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 57)
- The Exceptionally Able Youth Program, 1916-1973; VII.
  The largest part of the 1974 addition to the Civic Club records is about its Exceptionally Able Youth (EAY) Program. This program began in 1916 and continued until the Civic Club dissolved in 1974. Students from Allegheny County were chosen to take the EAY tests based on their class rank and combined SAT and Potential Leader Qualifications scores. The goal of the EAY Program was to encourage students with great potential to further their education after graduating high school. Although no scholarships were given directly, awardees were presented with a certificate during a small ceremony and could request letters of recommendation from the Civic Club for college application. In 1948, the EAY program introduced the Vocational Opportunities Division for students who did not wish to enter college but preferred education in a skilled trade. In 1970 and 1971 there was a failed movement to expand the EAY Program on a national scale.
  Included are news clippings; correspondence regarding principals, awardees, the EAY Committee, requests for financial support, and the EAY expansion plan; Awardees Meeting and EAY Committee Meeting minutes; reports about EAY effectiveness; and awardees lists. Blank student personal data forms, a test, certificates, and documents concerning EAY related events are also included, along with photographs of EAY participants in the 1920s and 1950s as well as EAY Awards Ceremonies from the 1970s.
  The records are arranged chronologically. A subseries was created for the 1972 nominee applications which are arranged alphabetically by school.
  - Programs, general, 1.
    - Exceptionally Able Youths History, undated (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Notice of Exceptionally Able Youths Testing, 1916 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Clippings, 1916-1926 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - List of Exceptionally Able Youths Awardees, 1921-1929 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Exceptionally Able Youth Committee Meeting Minutes, 1923-1939 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Photos of Exceptionally Able Youth Students, 1925, 1929, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Allegheny County Joint Committee on Scholarship Aid, 1926-1932 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Clippings, 1927-1929 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - "The Eugenic Aspects of the Pittsburgh Exceptionally Able Youths Movement" by Mary C. Warmbier, 1928 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Exceptionally Able Youths Press Releases, 1929-1950 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Reports on Scholarships, 1929 (Box 34, Folder 11)